saasit.com 2013-06-02

# Privacy Policy | FrontRange

## Commitment to privacy

FrontRange Solutions (“FrontRange”, “we”, “us”, and “our”) is a US-based corporation that provides world class IT and Customer Service software solutions, on a traditional premise software basis and a software-as-a-service (SaaS) basis. We provide on-premise, hosted, and SaaS software solutions to organizations (“you” and “your”) and your employees and consumers (“data subjects”) around the world.

The privacy of your data subjects is important to us. We are providing this policy to describe and explain our information practices and the measures we take to protect their privacy.  

## Scope of policy

We are a global organization that has developed data practices designed to appropriately protect the data of your data subjects. This privacy policy (“Policy”) describes how FrontRange Solutions Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively “FrontRange”) collects, protects, uses, and discloses personal data that it receives.

This Policy applies to the FrontRange on-premise, hosted, and SaaS services. This Policy also applies to FrontRange websites (“Sites”) [www.frontrange.com](http://www.frontrange.com/) and [www.saasit.com](http://www.saasit.com/) and other FrontRange-powered sites. SaaSIT is the online on-demand Solutions as a Service (“SaaS2”) version of FrontRange’s IT service management and client management software applications. These solutions are offered on a subscription basis and delivered online through the SaaSIT.com site on equipment, infrastructure, and in data centers provided by FrontRange or our subcontracted infrastructure-hosting service providers.

## Safe Harbor

FrontRange has been awarded the TRUSTe seal signifying their privacy policy and privacy practices complies with TRUSTe’s EU Safe Harbor program requirements which are consistent with the U.S. – EU & Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of personal information from the European Union and Switzerland.

FrontRange recognizes that the European Union and the United States have established a Safe Harbor Agreement pursuant to Directive 95/46/EC restricting the transfer and handling of personally identifiable information about individuals from the European Economic Area (EEA) to the United States. FrontRange has elected to adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles –- detailed below -- with respect to the collection, use, and disclosure of data from the EEA. From an EU perspective, we operate as a data processor, while you function as data controller. For more information about Safe Harbor Principles or to access our certification statement, please review the U.S. Department of Commerce's Web site at <http://export.gov/safeharbor/>.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Policy, you should first contact [privacy@frontrange.com](mailto:privacy@frontrange.com). If contacting us does not resolve your complaint, you may raise your complaint with TRUSTe by Internet at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php>, by mail at WatchDog Complaints, TRUSTe, 55 Second Street, 2nd Floor, San Francisco, CA, USA 94105, by phone at 415-520-3400, or by fax at 415-520-3420. If you are mailing TRUSTe to lodge a complaint, you must include the following information: the name of company, the alleged privacy violation, your contact information, and whether you would like the particulars of your complaint shared with the company. For information about TRUSTe or the operation of TRUSTe's dispute resolution process, see <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> or request this information from TRUSTe at any of the addresses listed above. The TRUSTe dispute resolution process shall be conducted in English.

## NOTICE PRINCIPLE

As your data processor, we make available to you this Policy so that you can better understand our data practices and whether they are consistent with privacy notices you have made available to your data subjects.

## DATA INTEGRITY PRINCIPLE

We ensure that the personal information we collect is relevant for the purposes for which we use it. We collect four main types of personal information:

  * **User information.** This is information collected about visitors to frontrange.com, saasit.com and FrontRange Connect such as name, business name, e-mail address, business address, title, job position, and phone number. We collect this information when you register to learn more about our products, request a demo or evaluation software, request or subscribe to newsletters, white papers, events, seminars, user groups, conferences or other services we might provide, or other information that you might provide to us in an online form, or when you contact us by e-mail or telephone. We use this information to respond to your requests and to promote our products and services. We also disclose leads to authorized third-party resellers.

If you choose to sign up for our FrontRange Connect community, we will require that you provide your name and email address, and you will have the option to provide additional personal information such as your address and phone number.

We also collect information about the computers that visit our sites, including:

    * _Web server logs_. These logs provide information such as what types of browsers are accessing our sites, what pages receive high traffic, and the times of day our servers experience significant load. We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the sites, track users’ movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. We use this information to improve the content and navigation features of our sites. We reserve the right to share aggregate and anonymous information with third-party service providers who assist us in data analysis.
    * _Cookies and tracking technologies._ A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this Site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our sites. We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our sites. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. We set a persistent cookie to store your passwords, so you don’t have to enter it more than once. Persistent cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance the experience on our site.
    * _Web beacons_. Third parties also employ Web beacons on our site. Web beacons are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of web users. Web beacons are embedded invisibly on webpages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We use a third-party tracking service which uses cookies and web beacons to track non-personally identifiable information about visitors to our sites in the aggregate to capture usage and volume statistics and to manage content.
  * **Business account information.** This is the business-contact information such as name, title, postal address, e-mail address, and phone number that we collect about people we serve or work with, including actual and prospective customers, alliance and channel partners, contractors, vendors and other parties interested in FrontRange or its products and services. Customers of FrontRange will automatically be included our Customer Support Portal portion of our Site, which may only be accessed via a personal login and password. When you access the portal as a customer, you will have the opportunity to review, correct, and update certain of your account information. Within the Customer Support Portal, a customer will find the terms of use for the Portal. We use this information to support your account, respond to your inquiries, perform accounting functions, provide you with information about us, our products, and services, and to otherwise maintain our business relationship with you.
  * **Customer proprietary database information.** This information is owned by the customer and entrusted to us to provide our services. FrontRange respects the privacy of all customer proprietary database information and views it as the customer’s property. This is information that you as a customer provide to us or direct us to collect your data subjects. We do not control what customer database information we may receive and host, nor what steps you as data controller have taken to ensure that the data is reliable for its intended use, accurate, complete, and current. FrontRange will use customer database information in order to fulfill our obligations under our SaaS subscription services agreement with the customer and to identify other FrontRange products which may benefit the customer. For instance, we may be engaged by the customer to help upload its data, to assist with configuration, or to provide support services. We will not use this customer data for marketing purposes. If you provide any personal data about your clients to FrontRange, you are responsible for providing any notices and obtaining any consents necessary for FrontRange to access and use that data.
  * **Applicant and employee information.** This is the typical information that is collected during employment relationships. For applicants, this includes your name, home address, personal telephone number, resume, and other information that you voluntarily provide when you submit an online job application. This information may be shared with our recruiting advisors as well as other third parties such as background-screening organizations involved in the assessment of your job application.

In addition to the data uses described above, FrontRange may use personal information for the following purposes:

  * _To respond to your requests_. These requests may include processing orders and processing downloads for whitepapers or product demonstrations or evaluations.
  * _To provide services to you_. These may include professional consulting, educational, maintenance and support services for which you have inquired or contracted.For instance, our as part of support services, our technical staff may require periodic access to services data to troubleshoot or monitor your system. We may provide technical support and related product information via the FrontRange Customer Support Portal. Our consulting services team may require access to your systems to implement our software solutions.; Any temporary copies of data accessed, used or created as a necessary part of this services are only maintained for time periods relevant to those purposes As part of these services, we may be required to remotely access your systems or an individual computer in order to troubleshoot a support issue or have direct physical access as part of an onsite engagement. We may also provide you product updates and notices.
  * _To provide informational services_. We may use personal data while providing online forums such as user groups and bulletin boards. We may also do so while delivering live or online events such as training seminars or conferences, including third-party events sponsored by FrontRange.
  * _To meet legal requirements_. FrontRange may be required to provide personal data to comply with legally mandated reporting, disclosure, or other legal process requirements. 
  * _To market our products and services_. We may inform you about our products, services or events and otherwise perform marketing activities.

## CHOICE PRINCIPLE

As your data processor, we will not share, sell, rent, or trade with third parties any personal information collected by us, other than as outlined in this privacy policy or unless you direct us to do so and have the appropriate authorization to do so.

If you have previously signed up to receive e-mailed information about our products, services, and special offers, and no longer wish to receive these communications you may opt out by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link, replying with ‘unsubscribe’ in the subject line in the e-mail e-mailing us at [unsubscribe@frontrange.com](mailto:unsubscribe@frontrange.com), or calling us at +1.800.755.2100. If you have signed up to receive information about our products, services and special offers via postal mail and no longer wish to receive these communications you may opt out by emailing us at [customer.support@frontrange.com](mailto:customer.support@frontrange.com) or contacting us at the address listed below.

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a colleague about our FrontRange community site, we will ask you for your colleague’s email address. We will automatically send your colleague a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. FrontRange Solutions does not store this information for the purpose of sending this one-time email. If you register for an account on FrontRange Connect, you will automatically be listed in our publicly accessible member directory. If you do not wish to be listed in the directory, please do not register for an account or contact us to have your account closed.

This is a United States Website and is subject to laws of the United States and the State of California. If you are customer who resides in the State of California, you have the right to request from FrontRange a list of third parties with whom we shared personally identifiable information about you for their own direct marketing purposes during the previous calendar year. FrontRange does not share personally identifiable information with unrelated third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. If you would like us to confirm this information in writing please send a request to us by email privacy@frontrange.com. You can also write to us at:

          Privacy Officer  
          FrontRange Solutions Inc.  
          490 N. McCarthy Blvd.  
          Milpitas, CA 93035  

## DATA ACCESS PRINCIPLE

Our SaaS system enables the customer to have full control over their personal information, whether to correct, update or delete personally identifiable information that they have collected and uploaded. If you receive a data-access request from a data subject about whom we host data and you would like our assistance in responding to that request, please contact privacy@FrontRange.com.

If your personally identifiable information, such as your email address, changes, or if you no longer desire our service, e-mail our Customer Care department at [customer.support@frontrange.com](mailto:customer.support@frontrange.com).

If you wish to change, update or delete your FrontRange Connect profile, or if you wish to request the deletion of an unauthorized profile you may do so by contacting us at [customer.support@frontrange.com](mailto:customer.support@frontrange.com). We will retain your FrontRange Connect information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services or longer as may be necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

We will respond to any request to access your personally identifiable information within 30 days.

## SECURITY PRINCIPLE

The security of personally identifiable information is very important to FrontRange. FrontRange takes reasonable physical, administrative, and technical measures to protect personal information under our control from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

In particular, we employ the following security measures, among others:

  * _Security policies_. We design and support our products and services according to documented security policies.
  * _Employee training and responsibilities_. We take certain steps to reduce the risks of human error, theft, fraud, and misuse of our facilities. We train our personnel on our privacy and security policies. We also require our employees to sign confidentiality agreements.

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about our security, you can contact us at [privacy@frontrange.com](mailto:privacy@frontrange.com). If we confirm that your Customer Information has been accessed or used by unauthorized individuals, we will contact your designated representative to coordinate our response to the incident.

## ONWARD TRANSFER PRINCIPLE

FrontRange may disclose personal data in the following circumstances:

  * To business partners and subcontractors as necessary in connection with the performance of requested services or solutions, or as otherwise appropriate in connection with a legitimate business need;
  * To service providers who host or facilitate the delivery of online training, seminars and webinars; email-delivery services and other technology providers; and third parties that may assist in the delivery of marketing materials, technical support services, or other products, services or other information;
  * With authorized reseller partners so that they may follow up with you regarding FrontRange products and services;
  * Job-applicant information may be shared with our recruiting advisors as well as other third parties involved in the assessment of your job application, such background screening organizations;
  * As necessary in connection with the sale or transfer of all or part of our business;
  * As required or permitted by law, or when we believe in our sole discretion that disclosure is necessary or appropriate to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, law-enforcement or government request, or other legal process; and
  * To any other third party with your affirmative consent.

In these situations, we will take reasonable steps to require the recipient of the data to protect the data in accordance with the relevant principles in the Safe Harbor or otherwise take steps to ensure that the EU and Swiss personal data is appropriately protected.

If FrontRange is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via e-mail or a prominent notice on our Site of any change in ownership or uses of your personally identifiable information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personally identifiable information.

**Crossborder data transfers**  
FrontRange is a global corporation with technical systems and processes that cross borders. Personal information collected on FrontRange systems may be transferred across state and country borders and stored or processed in the United States or any other country in which FrontRange, its subsidiaries, affiliates, or business units maintain facilities for the purposes of data consolidation, storage, and information management. By using our systems, your organization consents to any such transfer of information outside of your country of residence. FrontRange, its subsidiaries, affiliates, and business units will handle your information collected by our systems in a consistent manner, as described here, even if the laws in some countries may provide less protection for your information. Our privacy practices are designed to protect your personal information all over the world.

**Third-party websites**  
This Site contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the data collection, use practices, privacy statement, or cookie use of the sites that you have accessed from our Site. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each website that collects personally identifiable information. This Policy applies solely to information collected on this Website.  

## ENFORCEMENT PRINCIPLE

FrontRange maintains procedures for verifying that the commitments we make in this Policy to adhere to the Safe Harbor principles have been implemented. To do this, we complete an annual privacy compliance assessment and make improvements based on the results.

We also maintain a readily available and affordable independent-recourse mechanism so that each individual's privacy complaints and disputes can be investigated and resolved. To do this, FrontRange Solutions has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal. This seal signifies that this Policy and our data practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability, and choice regarding the collection and use of your personally identifiable information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our Statement or practices, please contact us at [privacy@frontrange.com](mailto:privacy@frontrange.com) or contact our Customer Care by calling +1.800.755.2100. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint). The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Website, and does not cover information that may be collected through software downloaded from the Website.

## Privacy Policy changes

We reserve the right to modify this Policy at any time. When we make only minor modifications, we may do so without notifying you. It is your responsibility to keep current the contact information we have on file for that designated representative. When we make material modifications affecting data practices where we operate as the data controller, we will post the new Policy on this Site under the “Privacy” link and notify you at the e-mail address specified in your account or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. The effective date at the top of this Policy will allow you to quickly know when the last changes were made.

**How you can contact us**  
If you have questions or concerns regarding this Statement, you should contact us by email at privacy@frontrange.com. You can also write to us at:

          Privacy Officer  
          FrontRange Solutions Inc.  
          490 N. McCarthy Blvd.  
          Milpitas, CA 93035

“While other solutions were clunky and not as streamlined, HEAT Cloud was a more mature product that integrated seamlessly into other applications.” 

VP of Information Systems

“FrontRange ITSM is the enterprise-class system we needed to pave the way for ITIL efficiency at the Laboratory.” 

“HEAT Cloud Service Management is part of our integrated solution that empowers our team with the tools and knowledge to deliver world-class service.” 

Senior Director of Software Development

“FrontRange Cloud is the most flexible, advanced and complete cloud ITSM solution available, enabling us to deliver world-class service to our clients, while increasing our operational efficiency managing our market-leading, cloud-based contact center software platform.” 

Vice President of Development
